in the 21st century the battle over
information has become a key part of War
a textbook example of this is the brutal
war that Israel has waged on Gaza since
October
2023 the Western media has spread many
misleading narratives echoing lies and
disinformation spread by the Israeli
government and this information War has
been used to justify war crimes and
crimes against humanity this January the
international court of justice at the
heg ruled that there is sufficient
evidence to investigate Israel on
charges of genocide against the
Palestinian people but to try to justify
these crimes against humanity the
Israeli government has spread the
extremely misleading claim that the
death toall in Gaza cannot be trusted Ed
because it's supposedly unreliable this
is completely false there have been
numerous scientific peer-reviewed
studies published by Leading experts in
the medical journal the lit showing that
the Gaza death toll reported by the
Palestinian Health Ministry is accurate
in this current war and has been
accurate in previous Wars I made a
separate video about that which I will
link to in the description below as of
the first effect February Israel has
killed more than
27,000 Palestinians and the vast
majority of the victims have been
civilians including more than 2third
have been women and children this is
according to the Palestinian health
ministries data and as I'll show today
this data is accurate however that is
not stopped US President Joe Biden from
repeating this blatantly false disinform
spread by the Israeli government is I
have no notion that the Palestinians are
telling the truth about how many people
are killed I'm sure innocence have been
killed and it's the price of waging a
war I think we should be incredibly
careful I think not we Israeli should be
incredibly careful to be sure that
they're focusing on going after the
folks that are the propagating this war
against Israel and uh and it's against
their interest when that doesn't happen
but I have no confidence in the number
that the Palestinians are using now
today I'm going to review the latest
evidence which shows how just ridiculous
this narrative is that has been spread
by the Israeli and the US governments
and that is the Revelation that the
Israeli government itself uses the
Palestinian Health ministry's own data
in Gaza in order to know what the death
toll is and Israeli intelligence agents
Israeli spies have admitted that the
Palestinian Health ministry's Data is
accurate so they know the Israeli
government knows that this death toll is
accurate but for political reasons
Israeli officials go out in the media
and they try to muddy the water and
falsely claim that the death toll was
fabricated by the Palestinian militant
group Hamas and they claim that it's all
fake and you cannot trust any of the
data that is completely absurd the fact
that the Israeli government itself uses
the data shows that they are simply
lying to try to justify their crimes
against humanity how do we know this
well a local media Outlet in Israel
called Sika meit published an article
revealing this now the report is in
Hebrew so I'm simply going to use the
auto translate into English just so you
know this is a machine translation but
it notes that the Israeli Army
investigated and found that the reports
of the dead of the Ministry of Health
and Gaza are reliable intelligence
sources told this Israeli journalist yal
aaham that the death toll is accurate
and that the the Israeli military itself
uses the Palestinian health ministries
data in its own internal reports now
this story was ignored by the vast
majority of the western media it only
got coverage in a few small sites but
one of the news outlets that did cover
it was vice vice news published a
follow-up report titled Israeli
intelligence has deemed Hamas run health
ministries death toll figures generally
accurate and they not only re-reported
what this Isel newspaper reported but
they also did some of their own
reporting over at Vice news I'm going to
go through some of the main points here
because they show how it's nonsense when
Israeli officials try to deny the death
toll that show that the vast majority of
Palestinians in Gaza who have been
killed have been civilians and in
particular women and children now Vice
news spoke with an anonymous Israeli
intelligence official who confirmed that
the Israeli government uses the Gaza
Ministry data and that the numbers were
accepted for inclusion in briefings for
senior Israeli officials and also two
officials from European intelligence
agencies from NATO members likewise said
that the Palestinian Health ministry's
data is used in official briefings
internationally now the anonymous
Israeli intelligence official told Vice
news that in the current war that Israel
is waging in which Israel has destroyed
most of gaza's infrastructure and
displaced about 2third of its population
The Rules of Engagement for the idf's
artill Hillary and Airborne assets have
been loosened and they said that the
secret services in Israel looked at the
Gaza health ministries collection
methods and determined the numbers were
generally credible and therefore the
Israeli government decided to use
hamas's numbers and they say Hamas but
it's the Palestinian Health Ministry
it's not just Hamas it's run by
Palestinian Health officials and they
note this Israeli official admitted
that the Palestinian Health Ministry is
generally transparent and credible with
civilian deaths however he noted that
they simply do not report the deaths of
Hamas Fighters and strategically this
makes sense because if Hamas released
the data about all of its fighters who
have been killed that could help Israel
in its planning for this war on Gaza so
the point is is that an Israeli
intelligence official is acknowledging
that the Gaza health ministries reports
on civilians killed in Gaza are accurate
that is to say its reports saying that
two over 2third of the Palestinians
killed in Gaza have been women and
children those are accurate according to
Israeli spies now furthermore this Vice
news report notes that the United
Nations office for the coordination of
humanitarian Affairs un OSHA also uses
this data in its reports and Vice news
spoke with two intelligence officials
from European NATO members and they also
said that the civilian casualty numbers
released by the ministry in Gaza were
accurate enough to be widely used in
intelligence briefings throughout NATO
they said Europe plays a major funding
role in the Gaza health system so we
have visibility into these operations
said one of the officials and therefore
the data is accurate he and actually
this intelligence official said that the
TR casualties are higher than any health
Ministry figures because there are
uncovered bodies half the Gaza Strip has
been flattened by Israel's air strikes
and there are more dead under the rebel
so this is confirming that if anything
not only is the Palestinian Health
Ministry data accurate it actually
undercounts the number of dead the tens
of thousands of Palestinians who have
been killed by Israel and furthermore
one of the NATO intelligence officials
said I'd be shocked if the Americans
were not using the same data in all of
their briefings as well and other
reporting shows this is exactly the case
The Huffington Post published a report
back in October noting that despite the
fact that President Biden tried to
downplay the Palestinian death toll in
Gaza claiming that they can't be trusted
in reality the US government itself the
state department uses the death toll of
the Palestinian Health Ministry inside
its own intelligence briefings and this
article in Huffington Post noted as of
October the 26th of October of 2023 in
at least 12 instances US Embassy
officials attributed the number of
Palestinian casualties to the Hamas
linked Health Ministry in Gaza including
in the report provided to State
Department colleagues on the 25th of
October hours before Biden make made his
ridiculous comments downplaying the
Palestinian death toll and trying to
cast it into doubt and this Huffington
Post report cited a document a cable in
which a Us official wrote that quote the
numbers are likely much higher according
to the UN and ngo's Reporting on the
situation so not only does the US
government use the Gaza Health
ministry's death toll but they also
admit that it's a conservative estimate
and the actual number of Palestinians
killed by Israel is even higher so all
of this goes to show that the death toll
as of the 1 of February that Israel has
killed more than
27,000 Palestinians not only is this
accurate it's very likely a conservative
estimate and once again more than 2third
of the casualties of the victims have
been women and children and the latest
figures are exactly
27,9 Palestinians and who have been
killed by Israel and
66,1 39 Palestinians who have been
wounded and ABC News published an
article it was a newswire by the
Associated Press that noted that South
Africa's foreign minister has accused
Israel of ignoring the ruling by the
United nation's top Court the
international court of justice which
ordered Israel to do all it can to
prevent deaths in Gaza and the
Associated Press noted that the number
of deaths has grown by more than
1,100 since the international court of
justice in the heg told Israel to do its
best to prevent acts of genocide against
Palestinians in Gaza so Israel is
continuing this genocidal campaign that
has the full support of the US
government which is complicit in these
crimes against humanity and in a
separate video which I will link to in
the description below I went through
some of the main points of this ruling
by the international court of justice at
the he and the icj stated very clearly
that Israel had to stop killing
Palestinians it had to stop causing
serious bodily or mental harm to
Palestinians that Israel had to take
immediate and effective measures to
enable the provision of urgently needed
basic services and humanitarian
assistance to Palestinians in Gaza that
Israel had to take effective measures to
prevent the destruction and ensure the
preservation of evidence related to
Israel's crimes so Israel is blatantly
violating this ruling from the
international court of justice at the
heg from the maximum senior legal
authority of the United Nations these
are latent contraventions of
international law and they show that
Israel is a rogue state so when you see
ridiculous Western media propaganda
trying to downplay the fact that with us
support Israel is killing tens of
thousands of Palestinian civilians in a
blatant Act of ethnic cleansing that the
heg itself has said Can constitute
potential genocide well you now know you
you're equipped with the evidence and
you can respond to them and say that
this is ridiculous you are simply trying
to make excuses for crimes against
humanity on that note I'm going to
conclude here I'm Ben Norton this is
geopolitical economy report I want to
thank everyone for joining me today
please like And subscribe if you're
watching the video on YouTube and if you
prefer listening to this you can check
out the geopolitical economy report
podcast once again I'm Ben Norton the
editor of geopolitical economy report I
want to thank you all for joining me I
will see you next time